Guide to the Benét Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1849-1973; 1920-1959; 2.83; 3 boxes
  - Writings by Members of the Benét Family
    - Benét, Laura
      - Basket for a Fair, poems, typescript and printed versions (photocopy), undated (Box 33, Folder 467)
      - "Behind the Bureau," story, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 468)
      - "The Benét Budget," [juvenalia?], autograph manuscript, undated (Box 33, Folder 469)
      - "Biographical Sketch of Laura Benét," draft, typescript, corrected and annotated, undated (Box 33, Folder 470)
      - "The Bird," poem, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 471)
      - "The Blue Alert," story, printed version, St. Nicholas, 1943 May (Box 33, Folder 472)
      - Bridge of a Single Hair, publicity, undated (Box 33, Folder 473)
      - "Christmas Eve," poem, printed version (4 copies), [1929?] (Box 33, Folder 474)
      - "Christmas Eve," poem, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 475)
      - "The Church of Dumb Creatures," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 476)
      - "Clover Coquette," poem, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 477)
      - "The Companion," poem, draft, typescript, annotated, undated (Box 33, Folder 478)
      - "A Daily Text Book," autograph manuscript, undated (Box 33, Folder 479)
      - "December Magnificat," poem, printed version, Boston Transcript, 1933 December 23 (Box 33, Folder 480)
      - "The Door," poem, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 481)
      - The Forge in the Forest by Padraic Colum, review, draft, autograph manuscript, [1925?] (Box 33, Folder 482)
      - "Frances Neill Rose, Daughter of William," obituary, autograph manuscript, corrected, [1940] (Box 33, Folder 483)
      - "Gardens of Babylon," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 484)
      - "The Ghost," poem, printed version, Voices, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 485)
      - "The Goat," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 486)
      - "The Goose Girl's Song," poem, printed version, Contemporary Verse, undated (Box 33, Folder 487)
      - "Grandmother's Preserve Closet," article, printed version, The Christian Science Monitor, 1946 October 24 (Box 33, Folder 488)
      - "Halloween Child: John Keats," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 489)
      - "The Harvest," story, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 490)
      - "Horseshoe Nails," story, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 491)
      - "Humor," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 492)
      - "Individual Song," review of High Mowing by Marion Canby, printed version, The Commonweal, 1932 June 15 (Box 33, Folder 493)
      - Is Morning Sure? Poems, printed version (photocopies), undated (Box 33, Folder 494)
      - "Joan," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 495)
      - "Marianne Moore, essay, typescript carbon, undated (Box 33, Folder 496)
      - "Merry Christmas!" poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 497)
      - "Mila and the Birds," poem, printed version, The Bookman, 1930 December (Box 33, Folder 498)
      - "The Mischievous Wings," story, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 499)
      - "Myself & I," poem, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 33, Folder 500)
      - "Narrative," essay, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 501)
      - "Nevermore… and Yet Forever," story, printed version, St. Nicholas, 1943 May (Box 33, Folder 502)
      - "Noah's Dove," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 503)
      - "A Novelist's 'Take-Off'," review of Witch Perkins by Evelyn Scott, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 504)
      - "Out of Bounds," poem, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 505)
      - "Plan," poem, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 506)
      - [Poems], drafts, typescript and autograph manuscript, undated (Box 33, Folder 507)
      - [Poems and other writings], printed versions, 1927-1933, undated (Box 33, Folder 508)
      - "The Ring," dialogue, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 509)
      - "Selected Poems by W. H. Davies," review, draft, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 33, Folder 510)
      - "The Story of Houdini," review, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 511)
      - "To Rachel at Ten," poem, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 512)
      - "The Tree," story, printed version, Household Magazine, 1931 August (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 721)
      - "The Turtle," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 513)
      - "Unknown Friend," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 514)
      - "When William Rose, Stephen Vincent, and I Were Young," drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 515)
      - "Who Can Say?" story, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 516)
      - "The Wife," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 517)
      - Miscellaneous writings, drafts fragments, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 518)
    - Benét, Rosemary
      - "Delightful Details of a French Child's Life," essay, printed verson, Ladies' Home Journal, 1928 August (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 722)
      - "French Children's Clothes are Pleasant," essay, printed version, Ladies' Home Journal, 1928 February (Box 34, Folder 519)
      - "In Blank Verse," poem, printed version, Forum, [?] January (Box 34, Folder 520)
      - "Les Morts," translation, draft, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 34, Folder 521)
      - "Our Paris Letter," printed versions, Town & Country, 1927-1929, undated (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 723-724)
      - "Pussy-cat, Pussy-cat, Where Have You Been?" essay, printed version, Harper's Bazaar, 1930 October (Box 34, Folder 522)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - "Dear Adolf," radio play, typecript mimeograph, 1952 August 2 (Box 34, Folder 523)
      - "Elementals," script, typescript and typescript carbon, annotated, 1957, undated (Box 34, Folder 523a)
        Includes letter, typescript, signed, concering the script from Malcolm Sharpe to Brandt & Brandt
      - "Good Old Medusa," play, printed version, The Younger Set, 1924 February (Box 34, Folder 524)
      - "Lunch-time Along Broadway," poem, printed version, S-4-N, 1920 July (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 725)
      - "Portrait [of a] Young F. Officer," autograph manuscript, undated (Box 34, Folder 525)
      - "Spanish bayonet," story, typescript carbon, undated (Box 34, Folder 526)
      - EMPTY folder (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 726)
      - "To James Walker Benét…" autograph manuscript, undated (Box 34, Folder 527)
      - Untitled poems, draft, typescript carbon, and printed version, 1933, undated (Box 34, Folder 528)
    - Benét, Thomas
      - "Speech to Town & Country Club," draft, computer printout, undated (Box 34, Folder 529)
      - Untitled, draft, computer printout, undated (Box 34, Folder 530)
    - Benét, William Rose
      - "Birds of the Air," poem, printed version, undated (Box 34, Folder 531)
      - "On the Decay of the Toy Theatre," poem, typescript, signed, undated (Box 34, Folder 532)
      - "A Person," poem, typescript, corrected and signed, 1940 September (Box 34, Folder 533)
      - "The Phoenix Nest," essay, printed version, Saturday Review, 1944 September 23 (Box 34, Folder 534)
    - Unidentified
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1849-1923, undated (Box 34, Folder 535-536)
  - Writings of Others
    - Bacon, Leonard
      - "In Memoriam: William Rose Benét," typescript, undated (Box 34, Folder 537)
      - "Lines," printed version, 1933 December 23 (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 727)
    - [Bangs, Edward?]
      - "The Yankee's Return from Camp," poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 34, Folder 538)
    - Barker, Elsa
      - [Poems], drafts, typescript and autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 34, Folder 539-540)
      - "The Secret Companions: A Story of the Supernatural," draft, typescript, undated (Box 34, Folder 541-542)
    - [Hively, Evelyn Helmick?]
      - "Rosemary Carr Benet: More Than Just Sweet," essay, [typescript photocopy?], undated (Box 34, Folder 543)
    - Johnson, Edith Warner
      - "Mask," poem, draft, typescript, undated (Box 34, Folder 544)
    - Keith, Joseph Joel
      - "As Brothers Are Remembered," tribute, printed version, [1943?] (Box 34, Folder 545)
    - Langham, Leslie
      - Untitled autobiogaphical narrative, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 34, Folder 546)
    - Nelson, Starr
      - "In the Boulder on the Shore," tribute, typescript, signed, 1950 October 10 (Box 34, Folder 547)
    - Post, G. Worthington
      - Untitled review of A Book of Americans, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 34, Folder 548)
    - Ridge, Lola
      - "Thermopylae," poem, printed version, undated (Box 34, Folder 549)
    - Thompson, Teresa Frances
      - Notebook, autograph manuscript, 1911 May (Box 34, Folder 550)
    - Undentified
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1942-1973, undated (Box 34, Folder 551)
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1914, undated (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 728)
- Other Papers, 1871-1994; 10.30; 20 boxes
  Organized into five subseries: Diaries, Financial and Legal Records, Photographs, Printed Material, and Other Material.
  Series III. Other Papers contains all other family-related material in the collection, including diaries, financial and legal records, photographs, and printed and other personal material. The series is arranged first by type of material and then, in most cases, alphabetically by family member.
  In addition to the large group of writings by Laura Benét in Series II., here there is a run of Laura Benét's diaries dating from 1922 through 1978--there is one volume for 1922, and then 25 volumes for the period from 1949 through 1978. Financial and legal records consist chiefly of bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts, tax documents, and other financial documents. While some photographs of Benét family members can be found here, a significanty number of photographs of Stephen Vincent and Rosemary Benét and their children are enclosed in letters from Rosemary Benét to her mother, Rachel H. Carr, and to her parents, Rachel H. and Thomas Carr. These letters, and enclosed photographs, are located in Series I. Correspondence.
  Printed materials include business and callings cards, clippings, invitations, programs, postcards, and other ephemera. There are also several volumes relating to Stephen Vincent Benét's graduating class at Yale, the Yale College class of 1919. Volumes such as The History of the Class of Nineteen Hundred & Nineteen (Yale University Press, 1919) provide biographical information on Benét and his classmates.
  Miscellaneous other materials include manuscript notes and notebooks, identification cards and passports, and school papers.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 56 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Diaries
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1935 (Box 35, Folder 552)
    - Benét, James Walker, [1902?]-1909 (Box 35, Folder 553-554)
    - Benét, Laura, 1922–1949 (Box 35, Folder 555-556)
      Includes material laid in
    - Benét, Laura, 1951–1957 (Box 36, Folder 557-560)
    - Benét, Laura, 1958–1961 (Box 37, Folder 561-564)
    - Benét, Laura, 1962–1965 (Box 38, Folder 565-568)
    - Benét, Laura, 1967–1970 (Box 39, Folder 569-572)
    - Benét, Laura, 1971–1974 (Box 40, Folder 573-576)
    - Benét, Laura, 1975–1978 (Box 41, Folder 577-580)
    - Benét, Laura Amanda (Walker), 1880–1898 (Box 41, Folder 581)
    - Mahon, Agnes, 1921–1924 (Box 42, Folder 582)
    - Unidentified, 1910 (Box 42, Folder 583)
  - Financial and Legal Records
    - Benét, Isabel, 1902 May 31 (Box 42, Folder 584)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1899–1930 (Box 42, Folder 585-586)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1925–1928 (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 729)
    - Benét, Laura, 1907–1962 (Box 42, Folder 587)
    - Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1879 September 19 (Box 42, Folder 588)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1930, undated (Box 42, Folder 589)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1927 March 17 (Box 42, Folder 590)
    - Mahon, Agnes I., 1924–1926 (Box 42, Folder 591)
    - Rose, Agnes M., 1871–1872 (Box 42, Folder 592)
    - Rose, Elizabeth Neill, 1922 December 19 (Box 42, Folder 593)
    - Unidentified, 1922-1926, undated (Box 42, Folder 594)
  - Photographs
    - [Benét, James Walker?], undated (Box 42, Folder 595)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1928, undated (Box 42, Folder 596)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1922-1936, undated (Box 42, Folder 597)
      Includes photographs of Benét's children and others
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent and others, undated (Box 42, Folder 597a)
    - Benét, William Rose, [1898?]-1920s (Box 42, Folder 598)
      Includes Elinor Wylie and unidentified others
    - Benét, William Rose, undated (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 730)
    - Benét family and children, 1916–1941 (Box 42, Folder 599-600)
    - Knox, Lillian Elizabeth, undated (Box 42, Folder 601)
    - Mahon, Agnes, undated (Box 42, Folder 602)
    - Murphy, Ethel Andrews, undated (Box 42, Folder 603)
    - [Rose, William John?], undated (Box 42, Folder 604)
    - Unidentified, circa 1880s-1914, undated (Box 43, Folder 605-608)
    - Places, undated (Box 43, Folder 609)
  - Printed Material
    - Business and calling cards
      - Benét, James Walker, undated (Box 43, Folder 610)
      - Benét, William Rose, 1906 July (Box 43, Folder 611)
      - Carr, Rachel H., undated (Box 43, Folder 612)
      - Others, undated (Box 43, Folder 613-614)
      - Miscellaneous removed from Katharine Jane Wiest and William H. McCrea Correspondence, undated (Box 43, Folder 615-618)
    - Clippings, 1871-1978, undated (Box 43, Folder 619-621)
    - Clippings, 1879-1994, undated (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 731)
    - Clippings removed from Agnes Mahon correspondence, undated (Box 43, Folder 622)
    - Events and programs, 1887-1922, undated (Box 44, Folder 623-624)
    - Greeting cards, undated (Box 44, Folder 625-635)
    - Invitations, 1901-1928, undated (Box 45, Folder 636)
    - Miscellaneous material removed from Agnes Mahon correspondence, undated (Box 45, Folder 637)
    - Miscellaneous material removed from Katharine Jane Wiest and William H. McCrea Correspondence, 1907, undated (Box 45, Folder 638)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 45, Folder 639)
    - Religious ephemera, 1917-1925, undated (Box 45, Folder 640-641)
    - Yale class books and material
      - Class of 1884, 1906 (Box 45, Folder 642)
      - Class of 1919 (Box 45, Folder 643)
      - Class of 1919, 1919–1946 (Box 46, Folder 644-650)
      - Class of 1949 (Box 47, Folder 651-654)
    - Other ephemera, 1873-1977, undated (Box 48, Folder 655-660)
    - Other ephemera, 1923-1946, undated (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 732)
  - Other Material
    - Benét, Frances Rose
      - Diary entry, 1933 July 22 (Box 48, Folder 661)
    - Benét, James
      - Album, 1914-1919, undated (Box 48, Folder 662)
    - Benét, James Walker
      - Certificates, 1883, 1921 (Box 49, Folder 663)
      - Commission, 1887 January 10 (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 733)
    - Benét, Laura
      - College diploma, 1907 June 12 (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 734)
      - Legal records, 1940, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 664)
      - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 49, Folder 665)
      - Medical records, [?] March (Box 49, Folder 666)
      - Miscellaneous "personal and P.R. material", 1935-1977, undated (Box 49, Folder 667)
      - Clippings removed from miscellaneous "personal and P.R. material", 1935, 1977 (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 735)
      - School papers, 1904-1907, undated (Box 49, Folder 668)
      - Scrapbook, 1912-1942, undated (Box 49, Folder 669)
        Includes correspondence and printed material
      - Scrapbook, 1932-1969, undated (Box 52, Folder 713-715)
        Includes clippings, printed ephemera, photographs, and correspondence
      - Material removed from scrapbook, 1951-1970, undated (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 736-737)
    - Benét, Laurence Vincent
      - Notebook, 1923-1929, undated (Box 49, Folder 670)
      - Material removed from notebook, 1910-1949, undated (Box 49, Folder 671)
    - Benét, Rosemary
      - Certificate of baptism, 1917 January 14 (Box 49, Folder 672)
      - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 49, Folder 673)
      - Notebook, undated (Box 49, Folder 674)
      - Passport, 1919–1920 (Box 49, Folder 675)
    - Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent)
      - Special passport, 1885 July 8 (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 738)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - "Benét/Paris/'20s" (videocassette), 1920-1929; 1 (Box 56, Item barcode 39002099369119)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Cancelled passport pages, [1920?], 1928 (Box 49, Folder 676)
      - "Christmas List", undated (Box 49, Folder 677)
      - Membership card, [1918?] (Box 49, Folder 678)
      - Printed ephemera, 1914 February 26 (Box 49, Folder 679)
      - School papers, undated (Box 50, Folder 680)
    - Benét, William Rose
      - "Baby's Record", 1886-1950, undated (Box 50, Folder 681)
    - Carr, Thomas
      - Civil service commission, 1904 March 11 (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 739)
      - Other papers, undated (Box 50, Folder 682)
    - [Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét)?]
      - School papers, 1923-1925, undated (Box 50, Folder 683)
    - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét)
      - School papers, 1924-1925, undated (Box 50, Folder 684)
    - Mahon, Agnes I.
      - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 685)
      - Medical records, 1907-1921, undated (Box 50, Folder 686)
    - Other
      - Drawings, undated (Box 50, Folder 687-688)
      - Drawings, undated (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 740)
      - Empty envelopes, 1898, undated (Box 50, Folder 689)
      - Empty folders, undated (Box 50, Folder 690)
      - Floral specimens, undated (Box 50, Folder 691)
      - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 692-696)
      - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 697-698)
      - Material relating to Watervliet Arsenal, 1942, undated (Box 51, Folder 699)
      - Clipping removed from material relating to Watervliet Arsenal, undated (Box 54 (Oversize), Folder 741)
      - Medallion, undated (Box 51, Folder 700)
      - Medical records, undated (Box 51, Folder 701)
      - Notebooks, undated (Box 51, Folder 702-705)
      - Piece of fabric, undated (Box 51, Folder 706)
      - School papers, 1904-1924, undated (Box 51, Folder 707-708)
      - Stamps, undated (Box 51, Folder 709)
      - Stationary, undated (Box 51, Folder 710)
      - Tissue paper, undated (Box 51, Folder 711)
      - Valentine cards and cutouts, undated (Box 51, Folder 712)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.42; 1 box
  Box 55: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - In Series I, Series III (Box 55, Folder 742-773)